# **Christophe Foyer**

christophe@cfoyer.com • www.cfoyer.com France: (+33) 6 78 56 99 03 • United States: (+1) 816-419-6150 French and US citizenships; Eligible to work without restriction in the USA and EEA

#### **Summary:**

Mechanical Engineering graduate with experience in projects in mechatronics, software, and aerospace engineering. Demonstrated track record of finding creative solutions to engineering challenges while operating under tight budgets.

• CAD, FEA and CFD

• Fabrication (metals, plastics, and composites)

Embedded systems

• Linux Server Management and Software Development

#### **Education:**

**RWTH Aachen** 

#### **Washington University in Saint Louis**

Saint Louis, United States

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering; Minor in Energy Engineering

Aug 2014 – Dec 2017 3.14/4.00 GPA

• Dean's List (Fall 2014, Fall 2017)

Study Abroad; 'Renewable Energy Technology' | 'Mechatronics and Product Innovation'

Aachen, Germany Jun 2017 – Jul 2017

**School for International Training** 

Reykjavik, Iceland

Study abroad in Renewable Energy Engineering and Resource Economics

Jun 2015 – Aug 2015

Lycée Sainte Marie Série S (Science track) Caen, France Sep 2010 – Jul 2013

• French Baccalauréat: "Mention Bien" (with honours)

# **Relevant Experience:**

#### **Tata Steel Europe**

IJmuiden, Netherlands

Mechanical Engineering Intern

 $Apr\ 2018-July\ 2018$ 

- Successfully built and implemented a real-time thermal simulation in Python reducing estimation error by 82.4%
- Estimating steel slab temperature within 21 degrees leading to potential savings of one million euros per year
- Organized a training session on collaborative code management (git) for the department

# Wash. U. Design/Build/Fly Competition Team

Washington University in St. Louis, USA

Co-Founder and Systems Team Lead

Mar 2016 – Dec 2017

Treasurer

Aug 2016 - May 2017

- Co-led the team to 12<sup>th</sup> place out of 138 teams at the AIAA DBF 2017 competition (1<sup>st</sup> in the US Midwest)
- Led the systems team to design and optimize aircraft internal systems through MATLAB simulations
- Managed an operating budget of \$10,000 to purchase components and organize travel to the competition
- Scheduled weekly meetings with the team and coordinated project deadlines

#### **American Society of Mechanical Engineers**

Washington University in St. Louis, USA

Sep 2016 – May 2017

• Researched and presented reasons to fund Michio Kaku's visit to campus for \$45,000; secured a date for his visit

• Advised ASME members with ongoing projects on manufacturing and component selection.

#### **Skills and Abilities:**

Event Planner

CAD / FEA / CFD: SolidWorks, Autodesk Inventor, AutoCAD, XFLR5

Programming Languages: Python, Matlab, Simulink, SQL, Arduino (C/C++), HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Fabrication: 3D-Printing (FDM), Machining (Lathe, Mill), Composite Manufacturing

Software: Microsoft Office Suite (Excel, Word), git, Windows, Linux

Languages: Bilingual French / English; Basic German and Icelandic

# **Academic Projects:**

#### Senior Design Project – Low-Cost CPV

Aug 2017 – Dec 2017

Foyer, Christophe; Rangwala, Adam; and Nana, Deep, "Water Lenses for Low-Cost Concentrator Photovoltaics" (2017). Mechanical Engineering Design Project Class. (https://openscholarship.wustl.edu/mems411/71/)

- Coding of FEA and ray tracing software for optics simulation in MATLAB
- Development of a sunlight tracking circuit and coding using Arduino
- Creation of a working proof of concept prototype increasing solar cell output by 860%

### **Independent Projects:**

## **Printable Folding Tricopter**

Jan 2018 – Apr 2018

Design of a folding tricopter frame for FDM printing:

- Design of interlocking printable parts using Solidworks and Autodesk Nettfab to be 3D-printed
- Designed to minimize weight and exterior volume while maximizing payload space

Aug 2017 – Dec 2017 **Motor Test Stand** 

Design and construction of a motor test stand for Wash. U Design/Build/Fly:

- GUI development, serial communication protocol and sensor integration
- Coded in Python and Arduino C, packaged in .exe format for easy deployment to new Windows installations
- Measures motor-propeller-battery system RPM, current, voltage, and thrust and logs output to CSV

Oct 2016 - Dec 2017 **Electric Longboard** 

Design and construction of a custom-built electric longboard:

- CAD, FEA, and part fabrication in aluminium and FDM printing of plastic parts
- Electrical powertrain design including component selection balancing efficiency and cost
- Designed according to air travel and personal transportation regulations

#### Naïve Bayes Classifier

Jun 2016 – Aug 2016

Coding of a Naïve Bayes Classifier for financial forecasting using machine learning:

- Coded a Bayesian classifier from scratch in python and tested it against other bayes classifiers on test datasets
- Achieved comparable performance while supporting missing datapoints

#### **IRIS Voice Recognition and Home Automation**

Jan 2015 - May 2017

Custom-built smart home and media centre system:

- Voice recognition using google API interfacing with connected microphones
- Coded in Python 2.7 on a Raspberry Pi running a Linux-based OS (added support for Windows and OSX)
- Control over house appliances and interfacing with Open Source Media Center

Dec 2013 - Jan 2015 **Robotics Test Platform** 

Design, coding, and construction of an internet-controlled robot used for autonomous sensing and navigation testing:

- Coded in Python on Linux-based microcontrollers
- Frontend: webpage coding in HTML and UI design
- Backend: hardware interfacing and communication over IP
- Experiments in visual odometry using OpenCV and ROS (ongoing)

## **Volunteering and Work Experience:**

**ICC** Ishinomaki, Japan May 2014 Volunteer

Construction of wooden terraces for the local community in a region devastated by the 2011 tsunami.

Domaine du Vivier Seasonal farm hand

Le Mesnil Mauger, France

Jun 2015 – Aug 2017

- Maintenance and operation of farming equipment and various agricultural work
- Driver for the tossing of the hay and the loading of hay bales during the summer